Floyd S. Fierman papers, ca. 1850-1997 (bulk: 1870 - 1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series I: New Mexico’s Jewish History
  - Congregation Albert (Albuquerque). (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Article - (Carmel, I.C.) "Laying of Cornerstone, Congregation Albert Synagogue By The Most Worshipful Grand Lodge Ancient Free and Accepted Masons of New Mexico" (May 13, 1978).
    Manuscript which addresses the synagogues in New Mexico.
    Article - "Twenty-Fifth Anniversary of Temple Albert To Be Observed This Week," (January, 14, 1923).
    Article - "First Synagogue At Albuquerque- 1900" (October 1978).
    Article - (Goldenstein, Raphael) "American Judaism in the Making: Story of Jewish Pioneers in the Building of New Mexico" (June 22, 1923).
    Article - (Altheimer, Louis) "Col. Louis Altheimer, Empire Builder" (November, 20, 1919).
    Article - "Congregation Albert Honors 90-Year Heritage" (September 12, 1987).
    Program for the twenty-fifth anniversary of Congregation Albert (January 18-21, 1923).
    Article - "Lost Albuquerque."
    Correspondence from J. Barsky (Congregation Albert librarian) to M. Amado regarding a book for an exhibit of "Synagogues of the Southwest."
    Inventory of B'nai B'rith Cemetery (1885-1958).
    Program for Temple Albert (1951).
    Articles which discuss the new rabbi of Congregation Albert ( Joseph R. Black) and the exit of the previous rabbi (Rabbi Paul J. Citrin).
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "Unwrapping a Legacy," New Mexico Jewish Link (November 1996).
    Article - "Temple to Install New Rabbi With Communitywide Service" (November 1996).
    Article - "Annual Book Fair to Feature Author, Historical Slide Show" (November 1996).
    Letter inviting Melissa Amado to the dedication of a historical marker at Congregation Albert.
    Article about Congregation Albert’s centennial celebration, with photographs.
  - Congregation B'nai Israel (Albuquerque). (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Correspondence between M. Amado and Congregation B'nai Israel.
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "Day School Opens With 23 Students" (September 1996).
    Pamphlet - "In Dedication To Fifty Years of B'nai Israel Sisterhood."
  - Congregation Chabad of New Mexico (Albuquerque and Santa Fe). (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Invitation for the Bar Mitzvah of Aaron Aviaz Chaves.
    (Congregation) Chabad of Santa Fe.
  - Congregation Mishkan Shalom (Roswell): Provides background and goals of this new congregation. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Congregation Montefiore (East Las Vegas). (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Pamphlet - "A Preliminary Checklist of American Jewish Institutions and Organizations Named In Honor of Sir Moses Montefiore."
    Original copy of Congregation Montefiore's appeal for aid to build a temple (1886).
    Original copy of the agreement of thirty one people to donate to the purchase of land for Congregation Montefiore.
    Copy of correspondence from J. Raisin to M. (February 3, 1911).
  - Danoff family. (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Interview with Isadore Danoff (June 17, 1988).
    Obituaries (2) for Sam J. Danoff (April 1973).
    Article - (Schwartz, Henry) "Jews of the West: Sam Danoff" (July 9, 1987).
    Manuscript by Robert Danoff; Biography of Sam Danoff.
    Article - "Mrs. Rose Danoff Funeral Monday" (November 11, 1956).
    Cattle brands; includes actual cattle brand and family name.
    Danoff, Hyman O. -"The Traders of the Southwest: The Danoffs of New Mexico" (July 1980).
    Biographical Sketch of Sidney Danoff (March 1992).
    Interview with Bertha Danoff (April 6, 1993).
    Article - Peterson, Art, "County's RTA Man Sydney Danoff Retires"
  - Danoff, Sam. (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Fierman's interview with Sam Danoff (November 25, 1970), type and manuscript format.
    Fierman's interview with Hy Danoff (February 13,1978).
    Brief, handwritten biography of Isaac Barth (born 1876).
    Fierman's manuscript notes concerning the Danoff family (November 27, 1975).
    Biographical manuscript of Sam Danoff (title and author unknown); includes notes.
    Citation for two sources from the American Jewish Archives on Sam Danoff.
    Official United States document appointing Sam Danoff Postmaster at Danoffville, New Mexico (April 1923).
    List of cattle brands.
    Article - "Sam Danoff-Southwestern Fiddler on the Roof," The Gallop NM Independent (August 9, 1972).
    Biography of Sam Danoff (includes photographs).
    Article - "Sam Danoff Well Known By Indians In Gallop Area," The Albuquerque Tribune.
    Correspondence from the National Archives to Fierman about Sam Danoff.
    Map of the Navajo and Hopi Indian reservations.
    Copy of the twenty-fifth wedding anniversary invitation of Rose and Sam Danoff (1939).
    Copy of the obituary for Rose Danoff (date unknown); and a copy of a reference to Sam Danoff and his new wife in the Gallop Independent (date unknown).
    United States Indian Service documents concerning Sam Danoff's application for a trader's license (1914-1915; from the National Archives).
  - Deming, NM: Book excerpt - (Hunter, M. J.) "The Story of Lottie Deno: Her Life and Times." (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Deno, Lottie. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    "The Filming of 'Lottie Deno;'" includes biography of Lottie Deno.
    McGaw, W.C. - "Was it Kosher What Lottie Did?," Southwest Saga (biography of Lottie Deno [born April 21, 1844]).
    Correspondence from Cynthia Rose to Abe Chanin (June 11, 1991) regarding the history of Deno Lottie.
  - Dittenhoefer, Abe ("Navajo Sam"). (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Copy of correspondence from Florence Dittendorfer Wolf to Rabbi Marcus regarding the Dittendorfer family. Also reference to her mother's family who remained in New York (April 1, 1961).
    Copy of a brief biography of Samuel Dittendorfer (author unknown) from the Bancroft Library, University of California-Berkley.
    Biography of "Navajo Sam" (Sam Dittendorfer) - discussion of his journey west and his interaction with the American Indians; from the American Jewish Archives (Cincinnati, Ohio).
    Copy of manuscript which tells a story of Billy the Kid and "Navajo Sam" (Samuel Dittendorfer); from Flora Spiegelberg - "Billy the Kid, The Cowboy Outlaw."
    Last two pages of a manuscript entitled "Heroes and Heroines." References to Josephine Sarah Marcus and Abe Dittendorfer; appears to be lecture notes.
  - Eckstein, Sam. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Eichwald: Reference to Eichwald in "American Judaism in the Making," (Rabbi Raphael Goldenstein), The American Hebrew, 22 (June 1923). (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "El Agricultor Moderno": Four pages from the Thursday March 23, 1916 El Agricultor Moderno; significant for the advertisements. This is said to be the only New Mexican newspaper with interest in agriculture and the raising of cattle. Also includes advertisements for Bernalillo Mercantile Company. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eldot/Eldodt: Rabbi Raphael Goldenstein - "American Judaism in the Making," The American Hebrew, 22 (June 1923); refers to Eldot and Fleischer. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Elsberg, Gustav: "The Promised Land," Albuquerque Journal, Section D, p.1, 3 (April 22, 1990; refers to Gustan Elsberg and Sol Floersheim). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Elsberg and Amberg, Emil. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Copy of correspondence from the Historical Society of New Mexico to Henry Woodruff (State Museum Curator). Refers to a couple of checks and a postcard which indicate correspondence between Elsberg and Amberg. A copy of the checks and the post card is included (April 18, 1924).
    Copy of correspondence from the Historical Society of New Mexico to Emil Amberg regarding information on Amberg and Elsberg.
    Three very small photographs; two watercolors for Jacob Amberg (1864) and Elsberg and Amberg's train coming into Sante Fe in October 1861.
  - Felsenthal, Louis. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Article - "A Western Picture Parade," Western States Jewish Historical Quarterly, vol. XI, no.1 (October 1978; contains brief note on Captain Louis Felsenthal and photograph).
    Copy of records from the court proceedings in Sante Fe, New Mexico; Louis Felsenthal (plaintiff) vs. W.S. Fletcher (defendant); includes affidavits, transcripts, and bonds (1890-1891).
  - Fleischer. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Floersheim family. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Floersheim family tree.
    Fierman, F. - "The Floersheims," Guts and Ruts (Ktav Publishing House, 1985); chapter on the Floersheim family-- specifically Sol Floersheim (copy and original manuscript).
    "Springer, New Mexico" - manuscript written by Carl Floersheim; discussion of Floersheim family; intensive concentration on the life of Sol Floersheim (January 1, 1959).
  - Floersheim, Sol. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Biography of Sol Floersheim by Fierman - "Sol Floersheim: Jewish Rancher and Merchant in Northern New Mexico," Western States Jewish Historical Quarterly; vol. XIV, no.4 (July, 1982).
    Biography of Sol Floersheim by Fierman - "Sol Floersheim: New Mexico Rancher."
    Fierman's manuscript notes regarding Sol Floersheim.
    Correspondence from Irma Floersheim to Fierman concerning the Floersheim family.
    Floersheim genealogy and scrapbook; organized by Fierman.
    Biography of Sol Floersheim by Fierman - "The Floersheims: The Story of a Ranching Jewish Family in Northern New Mexico."
    Correspondence from Abraham Shinedling to Jacob Marcus (Director of American Jewish Archives; November 26, 1957; includes a Description of the mercantile records of the Floersheim Mercantile Company; 1910 to 1947).
    Correspondence from Irma Floersheim to Rabbi Fierman in response to questions asked by Fierman (January 15, 1979; includes original and transcribed copy).
    Correspondence from Irma Floersheim to Rabbi Fierman (includes layout of Irma Floersheim's home).
    Correspondence from Fierman to Irma Floersheim (questions regarding the Floersheim family; May 17, 1978).
    Correspondence from the Western States Jewish Historical Quarterly to Fierman regarding his research on the Floersheim family (1982).
    Copy of a page of the Floersheim receipt book (1921).
    Article - "I Couldn't Make It Without Them, " The Grain Producers; APUBCO: Amarillo, Texas (July 1974; Description of the Jaritas Ranch, contemporary overview and historical background).
    Copy of warrantee deed from Solomon Floersheim to the Chico Springs Sanitorium Company (December 30, 1903).
    Copy of judicial District Court document which includes fees for court proceedings. The case involves Solomon Floersheim vs. Guarantee Trust Company, Chico Springs Ranch, and Resort Company (1901).
    Copy of notes from the annual meeting of the stockholders of Floersheim Mercantile Company (January 26, 1921).
    Copy of stock ledger of the Floersheim Company (1919-1920).
    Copy of business and inventory papers from the Floersheim Mercantile Company.
    Inventory of the archive file "Floersheim Mercantile Company Business Records: 1899-1969."
    American Jewish Archives questionnaire on Carl Floersheim (October 27, 1958).
    Book excerpt - The Roy Story (by F. Stanley). Includes notes from F. Fierman.
    Copy of the deed from the Floersheim Papers at the University of New Mexico Library (September 6, 1897).
    Article -"Pioneer Springer Concern Observes Their Golden Anniversary" (December 4, 1947).
    Transcript of conversation between F. Fierman and A. Floersheim (September 18, 1978).
    Handwritten version of telephone conversation between F. Fierman and Don Floersheim.
    Handwritten copy of "Floersheim Store To Close: An Era Ends in Roy" (April 27, 1968).
  - Fort Griffin, NM: Book excerpt - "The Story of Lottie Deno: Her Life and Times," by J. Marvin Hunter. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Frank, Anne. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Frankel, E. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Franzblau, Abraham. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Freudenthal, Carmen. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Article - (Bordonaro, Deborah) "Activist Leaves Behind An Important Legacy" (July 18, 1991).
    Autobiography of Carmen Freudenthal.
  - Freudenthal Club Bulletin: Copies of the "Freudenthal Club Bulletin". (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Freudenthal family. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Correspondence from W.J. Parish to L.E. Freudenthal (March 8, 1960).
    Correspondence from L.E. Freudenthal about the Freudenthal family (August 25, 1953).
    Index to the Freudenthal Family Papers (1837-1975). Rio Grande Historical Collections NMSU Library.
  - Freudenthal genealogy: Genealogy of the Freudenthal family (1786-1951). (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Freudenthal, Rabbi Leopold. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Book Excerpt - (Rochlin, Harry) Pioneer Jews. (Houghton Mifflin: Boston; 1984).
    Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923).
  - Freudenthal, Louis. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Correspondence from Carmen Freudenthal to F. Fierman (July 1971).
    Obituary of Louis Freudenthal.
    Manuscript by Louis Freudenthal on the history of his life.
  - Freudenthal, Morris. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Article - (Freudenthal, Louis E.) "The Don Bernardo Hotel: A Short Story" (June 1967).
    Copy of receipts and correspondence from L.B. Freudenthal and Company (1891).
    Copy of correspondence to L.B. Freudenthal and Company (1891-1894).
  - Freudenthal, Phoebus: Copy of the biography of Phoebus Freudenthal. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Freudenthal, Samuel. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Correspondence from Fannie Freudenthal to F. Fierman (August 8, 1964).
    Copy of obituary for Samuel Fruedenthal (November, 22, 1939).
    Correspondence from Walter Freudenthal to F. Fierman (October 18, 1965).
    Autobiography of Samuel J. Freudenthal (1863-1939).
  - Freudenthal, Dr. Wolff: Untitled article written for the Jewish Daily Forward. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Frey, Rabbi Sigmund: Article - (Axe, Ruth Frey) "Dr. Sigmund Frey, Third Rabbi of Montefiore Congregation of Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1889 and 1890." (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Friedman, Rabbi William S.: Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "G" surnames, various: Gold, Gould, Gudsorf, Grunfield: Copies of card catalog references in New Mexico State Records and Archives. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Gildersleeve and Knaebel: aarCopy of Gildersleeve and Knaebel sales receipts (1875-1881). (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Gold, Louis (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Copy of legal documents concerning the case of the Territory of New Mexico vs. Louis Gold (1871).
    Copy of the Census of 1870 - New Mexico Territory, Sante Fe County, Sante Fe Precinct #4.
    Copy of one page of the Records of the Territorial Auditor (August 13, 1867).
    Article - "Society Minutes, 1859-1863," New Mexico Historical Review.
    Court papers from the New Mexico Territorial Supreme Court: United States vs. A. Gold (1871).
    Article - Brief history of Moses Aaron Gold (January 6, 1881).
    Copy of New Mexico Territorial Supreme Court records: United States vs. M.A. Gold (1872). Copy of miscellaneous court documents (1857-1864).
    Copy of 28th Legislative Assembly (December 31, 1888- February 28, 1889; in Spanish).
    Copy of two handwritten pages (in Spanish) - Marriages in Sante Fe (1883).
    Copy of documents -"Council Journal" (January 26, 1887), "Executive Office" (February 19, 1896).
    Copy of "Indirect Index to Deeds--Santa Fe, New Mexico" (1881-1905).
    Copy of "Territorial Auditors' License Records re: Gold Family" (1883-1894).
    Copy of an adjustment of the account of the county clerk and tax collector for Santa Fe county (March 18 to July 1, 1859).
    Manuscript notes written by F. Fierman about Louis Gold.
    Copy of card catalog references - New Mexico State Records Center and Archives.
  - Gold Court Records, New Mexico (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Manuscript - "Termino de Julio- 1858."
    Correspondence from the archivist at the State of New Mexico State Records Center and Archives to F. Fierman (September 29, 1987).
    Correspondence from the archivist at the State of New Mexico State Records Center and Archives to A. Davis (February 8, 1967).
    Original correspondence from A. Davis to F. Fierman (February 15, 1967).
    Correspondence to F. Fierman regarding the Gold family. Only pages two and three available.
    Correspondence to F. Fierman from A. Davis (November 28, 1965).
    Correspondence between A. Davis and Dorothy (last name unknown; January 24, 1966; also copy of a card from Gold's General Store; March 24, 1901).
    Correspondence from the archivist at the State of New Mexico State Records Center and Archives to F. Fierman (April 3, 1967).
    Several correspondences from A. Davis to F. Fierman concerning the Gold family (1965).
  - Goldberg, Samuel. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Original correspondence from the archivist at the State of New Mexico State Records Center and Archives to F. Fierman (February 28, 1978).
    "Make Good Soldiers" from the Sharlot Hall Scrapbook (Prescott, Arizona).
  - Goldenstein, Rabbi Raphael: Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Goodman, Manny: Article - (Conaway, J.) "Old Town Trader Hitched His Wagon to a Star" (August 16, 1987). (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Gottlieb, Rabbi Lynn: Article - (Libman, N.) "Resistance, Reconstruction and a Rabbi: Gottlieb Celebrates 25th Year at the Pulpit" (September, 1997). (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Great River: The Rio Grande in North American History" (Paul Horgan). (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Partial copy of "Great River- The Rio Grande in North American History."
    Partial copy of "A History of the Jews in New Mexico" (by Henry Tobias), University of New Mexico Press: Albuquerque.
    Partial copy from "New Mexico Place Names: A Geographical Dictionary" (edited by T.M. Pierce; University of New Mexico Press).
  - Greenberg, Rabbi Dr. William H.: Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Grunsfeld, Albert. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Copy of legal documents regarding the case of the Territory of New Mexico vs A. Grunsfeld (1877-1878).
    Copy of legal documents describing the case of the Grunsfeld Brothers vs D.R. Brownell (1904).
    Copy of obituary for Albert Grunsfeld (December 3, 1893).
    Copy of the notification of the death of Albert Grunsfeld (April 6, 1921).
  - Grunsfeld, Alfred: Article - (Godenstein, Rabbi Raphael) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Gusdorf family (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Copy of card catalog reference entitled "Gusdorf Brothers- Papers" - American Jewish Archives.
    Inventory of notes receivable (1917-1918).
    F. Fierman's notes on the Gusdorf family.
    Scribbled calculations from the Office of Gusdorf Bros. (April 2, 189-).
    Copy of correspondence to Francis Wilson from Margaret Hale (June 22, 1923).
    Copy of the power of attorney documentation from Alexander Gusdorf (June 20, 1923).
    Copy of contract between Alexander Gusdorf and Ralph Pearson (September 7, 1918).
    Copy of correspondence to and from Francis Wilson (1923).
    Copy of declaration of court proceedings: the State of New Mexico and Gerson Gusdorf vs. the unknown heirs of Lucien B. Maxwell, Guillermo Trujillo, Jose Dolores Quisnel, Desideria Pacheco de Barron, Donaciano Quisnel, Teresita S. de Quisnel, Minnie Quisnel de Trujillo, and all other unknown claimants.
    Copy of the final judgment of the District Court, County of Taos, Territory of New Mexico in the case of Adair vs Baell (February 5, 1902).
    Copy of the certification of the death of J.Gistdorf (sic) (July 8, 1891).
    Copy of a statement by the administrator of Joseph Gusdorf's will (in Spanish; July 13, 1891).
    Legal documents pertaining to the will of Joseph Gusdorf (July 1891).
  - Gusdorf family (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Article - "Pioneer Taos Women Rap Council on Car Meter Plan" (July 19, 1959).
    Article - "From Immigrant Bride to Bank President: Mrs. Bertha Gusdorf," by J. A. Burns (October 17, 1991).
    Legal document stating that Alexander Gusdorf turn all of his real estate, personal property, credits, and effects to exonerate his debts (January 19, 1898).
    Article - (James, Rebecca Salsbury) "Gerson Gusdorf: The Business Man With the Taste of An Artist" (March 15, 1951).
    Biography of Gerson Gusdorf (1869-1951).
    Manuscript - "Alexander Gusdorf."
    Biography of Gerson Gusdorf.
    Gusdrof Ledgers from Taos, New Mexico (1896-1918).
    Original manuscript entitled "Sadok Staab and Alexander Gusdorf," written by F. Fierman.
    Card catalog references to the Gusdorf family.
    Copy of part of the ledger "B" of Gusdorf Brothers (January 1, 1894).
    Biographies of Gerson and Alexander Gusdorf.
    Copy of merchant correspondence all signed by Alexander Gusdorf (1903).
  - Havura Ivrim Congregation (La Jara). (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Correspondence from Gershon Winkler to Melissa Amado (January 29, 1995).
    Correspondence from Melissa Amado to Gershon Winkler in response to a previous letter (February 15, 1995).
  - Helman, Rabbi Leonard A.: Article - (Zimmerman, Rebecca) "Rabbi Helman Leaving Santa Fe" (June 1991). (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Heritage of New Mexico: Newsletter which deals with New Mexico's heritage. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hersch family. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Correspondence to F. Fierman from State of New Mexico State Records Center and Archives (December 29, 1977).
    Correspondence from Herminia Gonzales to F. Fierman (October 25, 1973).
    Notes written by F. Fierman with regard to Joseph Hersch.
    Copy of section of deed records from Sante Fe County.
    Copy of several pages of the Indirect Index to Deeds (Sante Fe County, New Mexico; 1848-1934).
  - Herz, Cary: Article - "A Photographer's Crypto-Jew Work Gets California Audience" (March, 1997). (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Herzstein family: Article - "The Promised Land" (April 22, 1990). (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Hiat, Alice: Newspaper article discusses Alice Hiat's Jewish art. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Holocaust: Articles which discusses Holocaust memorials. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Humanistic Judaism (in Albuquerque): Article - (Milstein, T.) "Humanist Jews to Form A Local Congregation." (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Ilfeld family. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Genealogy of the Ilfeld family (1780-1965); compiled September 20, 1971 by Max Ilfeld.
    Copy of advertisement for Ilfeld's Council Cigars.
    Copy of advertisement from Ilfeld and Company (New Mexico, May 17, 1884).
    Article - "Brief Biographical Notes on Herman Ilfeld Bacharach February 1983," by Diane G.Stein.
    Notes written by F. Fierman in regard to the Ilfeld family.
    Unidentified inventory of the William C. Ilfeld Collection.
    Article - "Seventy Years of Progress: Founding and Development of Charles Ilfeld Company 1865-1935" (July 25, 1935).
    Copy of the Ilfeld inventory of the University of New Mexico; with correspondence from Barron Oder to F. Fierman.
    Inventories of the Ilfeld Company.
    Inventory list of the W.C. Ilfeld Film Collection (February 6, 1973).
    Correspondence from Frederic Ilfeld to F. Fierman (February 4, 1964).
    Correspondence from Mrs. Samuel W. Adleman to F. Fierman (January 14, 1983).
    Obituary for Louis Ilfeld (March 30, 1950).
    Obituary for Bertha R. Ilfeld (November 12, 1992).
    Article - (O'Grady, J.) "The Pioneer Ilfelds- Working Hard, Long, and Smart," (October 1982).
    Correspondence from Melissa Amado to Frederick Ilfeld.
    Article - "The Promised Land" (April 1990).
    Correspondence between Jacob Marcus and Louis C. Ilfeld (April 14, 1944 and May 17, 1948).
    Article - "First Goods for the Charles Ilfeld Co. Carried to Las Vegas on 75 Burros," by Arch Napier.
    Biographical information on the Ilfeld family.
    Article - "First Goods For the Charles Ilfeld Co. Carried To Las Vegas on 75 Burros" (by Arch Napier).
  - Ilfeld, Louis. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Article - "Charles Ilfeld's Story is History of New Mexico."